hi everyone I'm dr. Andy Galvan and
welcome back to another episode of
5-minute physiology right take a complex
physiological idea and give you
everything you know you need to know
about it in five minutes or less
today's topic is muscle fiber types to
understand what we're talking about here
we have to realize it in human skeletal
muscle all of your muscles are made up
actually have a whole bunch of smaller
individual muscle fibers think of it
like a ponytail so you have one ponytail
but that's actually made up of hundreds
if not thousands of individual muscle
fibers or in the ponytail example
individual hairs so if I were to take
your quadricep or one of your quadriceps
muscles that individual muscle is made
up of hundreds if not thousands of
individual muscle fibers well in humans
the fiber type in the muscle is
different between each fiber or each
cell so in the case of say the quadricep
well we know it's actually about half of
your fibers or nobody called slow twitch
and maybe half of them are fast twitch
that's different from something like
your soleus which is one of your calf
muscles your kid your soleus is actually
maybe something more like 80% slow
twitch and 20% faster so if there were a
hundred total fibers in it each of them
would be what we would call fast tricked
or slow twitch and twenty would be
faster
all right so we have a basic
understanding what does a fiber type
spark but let's expand on that a little
bit more so what we did say actually
here from from my high tech chart is
isn't actually three fiber types
so I sent fast but too slow to its but
it gets a little bit more complex than
that
starting over here with your first shear
type or what we call your type 1 or your
slow to it moving down on our continuum
we see our two A's which are also pure
but then these are not your fast twitch
fibers then we have a third fiber type
which are your two x's these are also
fast big twitch but these are even more
fast twitch than your two ways so you
have type one type two ways with your
fast twitch and type two X which are
really fast switched and the two ways
are pretty close to the two x's a a
little bit different now just like in
the rest of the world it's not quite
that easy what we tend to see actually
happen is there are some fibers that are
in between these two so this would be an
individual muscle fiber or mild fiber
muscle cell that is both fast twitch and
slow twitch at the same time or it could
be both fast twitch and mega fast twitch
so this could be something like over
here where you could have one individual
muscle fiber that would be one to a yeah
this is one cell and it could be half
fast and half slow or 80% slow and 20%
faster or somewhere along the spectrum
it could be over here or over here it'd
still be a little bit of both we can
have another hybrid over here again
which could be a 2a and partially a 2x
all right we would call these as I've
been mentioning
hybrid fighters all right just like your
automobile
that's half gas half electric these
things are half fast half slow or how
fast five mega fast until we call them
hybrids now where this is really
interesting is we don't know the picture
entirely but what we do realize what
happens is the more sedentary or
inactive you are with your physical
activity the more of these hybrid fibers
you get in both cases hybrid fast fibers
are in fact what we see happen is we
almost never see people have these pr2
X's almost ever well then we're looking
at young old men women strength train
endurance train you name it we don't
have received its in fact the percentage
that we see in our lab of something like
0.1% maybe nuts this is one every 1000
individual vibrators appear to mechs but
we see a ton of to eight sizes
especially if you're untrained or even
moderately happy okay so basically
what's happening is we don't know
exactly but we can theorize it and you
become less physically trained your two
ways start converting into 282 X your
ones start being converted and you want
to wait to it so we don't know exactly
why these fibers turn into hybrids I
could guess with min you'll save that
for another video the quick answer is
potentially that's sort of saying you
know you aren't using this so you don't
know what you want us to do so we're
gonna hang on the middle until you tell
us how you want to function you want us
to be very fatigue resistant will become
a like one you'll have to be very fast
which will be coming back - I know
that's gas and we can talk in more
detail later in one of our other
segments maybe are 25 or 55
physiology second okay so if we become
an active we gain one of these hybrids
and it actually doesn't matter what we
do activity wise whether we strength
trained you intervals one swim two
endurance training but whatever we were
any kind of physical activity we see the
exact opposite where now please start
turning back into here all right so we
see our hybrid 282 X's we convert into
two eight again we don't go to 2x those
are basically we know that they're
physiologically possible but extremely
rare you don't gain a with training we
don't lose them really they're just
pretty much it on the picture our to a
2x escalated to a probably some of our
one two ways also probably go into to a
or they go into type one depending on
what we do exactly now I've got a lot
more to learn about this we have got
very little information on anaerobic
athletes strength training athletes
power speed athletes so we don't know
exactly the picture here more research
is needed but this is really
unquestionable so the last thing we'll
talk about here very quickly is its it's
really we can't argue anymore whether or
not we can convert either of these
hybrids in the two legs right we don't
see as much conversion into type ones
but we do see it happening but it's
probably less problem so that's your
five minute physiology talking about
muscle fiber types of humans get them in
socially they have Danny bag dark rainy
Gotham calm and check out the website
stay tuned for the next video let me
know if you have any questions about
this and let me know what topics you
want to see next and we'll see you back
next time
you